<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shon Inouye</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shon Inouye</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitch Analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/twitch-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/twitch-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Twitch Analysis Twitch.tv has gained massive popularity in recent years and is currently the world&amp;rsquo;s leading video live streaming service. The site primarily focuses on video game live streaming and broadcasts of esports competitions, but is also home to music broadcasts, creative content, and more recently, &amp;ldquo;in real life&amp;rdquo; streams.
This project is an ongoing analysis of Twitch data utilizing Python in an effort to understand the trends and habits of popular streamers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Analysis — African American Achievements</title>
      <link>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-african-american-achievements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-african-american-achievements/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This week’s Tidy Tuesday data consists of data on African American achievements throughout history. Given the recent events surrounding the Black Lives Matter movement, it seems fitting that we take some time to recognize the achievements of Black individuals and bring attention to the racism that they have faced and continue to face. You can take a look at this week’s data and how it was collected on the Tidy Tuesday GitHub repo:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Dashboard</title>
      <link>/projects/covid-19-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/covid-19-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>This dashboard takes data from the COVID-19 Data Repository by the Center for Systems Science and Engineering (CSSE) at Johns Hopkins University. I periodically run an R script that extracts data from the repo, cleans it, and uploads it to a PostgreSQL database on AWS. The scripts for the Shiny dashboard connect to that database and produce the dashboards that are then hosted on shinyapps.io.
View the official dashboard here: https://shoninouye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Analysis - GDPR Violations</title>
      <link>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-gdpr-violations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-gdpr-violations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Data protection and privacy is a growing concern for many as we move into a society where data can be monetized and utilized across a wide range of fields. This week’s Tidy Tuesday data consists of GDPR violations from Privacy Affairs. From the Tidy Tuesday GitHub repo and related Wikipedia article:
 The General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR) is a regulation in EU law on data protection and privacy in the European Union (EU) and the European Economic Area (EEA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Analysis - Hip-hop Ratings</title>
      <link>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-hip-hop-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-hip-hop-ratings/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This Tidy Tuesday analysis revolves around hip-hop data and song ratings by critics within the genre. From the Tidy Tuesday GitHub repo and related article:
 Earlier this year, BBC Music asked more than 100 critics, artists, and other music industry folks from 15 countries for their five favorite hip-hop tracks. Then they broke down the results of the poll into one definitive list. But BBC Music didn’t just publish a best-of list, they also published the complete poll results and a description of the simple algorithm they ranked the songs with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Analysis - Tour de France</title>
      <link>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-tour-de-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidy-tuesday-analysis-tour-de-france/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Tuesday This is my first (published) analysis of Tidy Tuesday data. Tidy Tuesday is a data project that allows anyone to practice their wrangling and data visualization skills on weekly posted datasets. Check out out the Tidy Tuesday GitHub repo to learn more and #TidyTuesday on Twitter to see some examples.
 Tour de France - Intro This Tidy Tuesday analysis revolves around Tour de France data. Tour de France is the world’s most prestegious and difficult bicycle race that occurs every summer in France.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>